<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oidc on 6equj5.dev</title>
    <link>https://salrashid123.github.io/tags/oidc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oidc on 6equj5.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 14:34:01 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://salrashid123.github.io/tags/oidc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling Cloud Composer &gt; GCF &gt; Composer securely</title>
      <link>https://salrashid123.github.io/posts/composer_gcf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 14:34:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://salrashid123.github.io/posts/composer_gcf/</guid>
      <description>Sample Cloud Composer (Apache Airflow) configuration to securely invoke Cloud Functions or Cloud Run.
In addition this sample shows inverse: how Cloud Functions can invoke a Composer DAG securely. While GCF-&amp;gt;Composer is documented here, the configuration detailed here is minimal and (to me), easier to read.
Anyway, the following will setup cloud composer, then we will trigger composer to invoke a cloud function&amp;hellip;the cloud function will just trigger a different cloud composer endpoint&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic OIDC:  Using Cloud Scheduler, Tasks, and PubSub to make authenticated calls to Cloud Run, Cloud Functions or your Server</title>
      <link>https://salrashid123.github.io/posts/automatic_oidc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 14:34:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://salrashid123.github.io/posts/automatic_oidc/</guid>
      <description>This is a second in a series related to a versatile feature in Cloud Scheduler and Cloud Tasks and Cloud PubSub that automatically emits google OpenIDConnect and oauth2 access_token to outbound webhook calls. When a Scheduled task fires and calls an HTTP endpoint, it can automatically carry credentials to authenticate itself. The id_token credential can then get validated at the HTTP web-hook target using well known techniques (i.,e validate the signature and aud: fields in the token).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>