<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloudrun on 6equj5.dev</title>
    <link>https://salrashid123.github.io/tags/cloudrun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloudrun on 6equj5.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 14:34:01 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://salrashid123.github.io/tags/cloudrun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic OIDC:  Using Cloud Scheduler, Tasks, and PubSub to make authenticated calls to Cloud Run, Cloud Functions or your Server</title>
      <link>https://salrashid123.github.io/posts/automatic_oidc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 14:34:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://salrashid123.github.io/posts/automatic_oidc/</guid>
      <description>This is a second in a series related to a versatile feature in Cloud Scheduler and Cloud Tasks and Cloud PubSub that automatically emits google OpenIDConnect and oauth2 access_token to outbound webhook calls. When a Scheduled task fires and calls an HTTP endpoint, it can automatically carry credentials to authenticate itself. The id_token credential can then get validated at the HTTP web-hook target using well known techniques (i.,e validate the signature and aud: fields in the token).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPG stream encryption and decryption on Google Cloud Functions and Cloud Run</title>
      <link>https://salrashid123.github.io/posts/gpg_gcf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 14:34:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://salrashid123.github.io/posts/gpg_gcf/</guid>
      <description>About a year+ ago a colleague of mine (Daz Wilkin) asked me how best to decompress/unzip a file using Google Cloud Functions. The suggestion ended as a sample he provided demonstrating the stream-read-&amp;gt;stream-write pattern with the pertinent input-outputs (input: unziped file; output zipped file). The distinct advantage of stream processing the unzip function is that the data is never held in memory: as the unzipped content gets processed by GCF, its promptly written as a zip file to GCS.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>